JENNA AHART

SCIENCE WRITING AND COMMUNICATIONS

(484) 273 8244



✓ JENNAAHART@GWU.EDU

professional profile

I am a senior at the George Washington University, pursuing a unique academic combination of journalism and astrophysics. With a background in writing, graphic design, data analysis, and data visualization, I have honed my ability to create accessible scientific content for diverse audiences. My prior work at NASA, an aviation engineering firm, and my university's undergraduate research program has underscored my drive for fostering a well-informed public through effective science communications.

See my full portfolio: https://jennaahart.wixsite.com/portfolio/projects

education

Graduating May 2024 **BA IN JOURNALISM & MASS COMMUNICATIONS MINOR IN ASTROPHYSICS** GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY GPA: 3.9/4.0

professional experience

June - August 2023

NASA Fermi Astrophysics Communications Intern | NASA GSFC, Greenbelt, MD

- Wrote web and news features on high-energy astrophysics discoveries for NASA Universe site
- Translated science team's ongoing research into public-friendly prose
- Created social media campaign to celebrate Fermi telescope's 15-year anniversary, including graphic design and copywriting
- Redesigned mission website for a modern, user-friendly experience

May 2022 – Present

Marketing Intern | Arora Engineers, Chadds Ford, PA

- Write and edit over 400 aviation engineering project profiles for a layperson audience
- Perform website design and copyediting during rebranding stage
- Write and design social media posts to celebrate company achievements

Jan 2022 - May 2023

Communications Assistant | Corcoran School of the Arts and Design, Washington, DC

- Wrote press releases and articles for new exhibition and faculty announcements
- Chiefly managed social media presence

Jan 2022 - Present

Site Director | GW Scope, Washington, DC

- Chiefly run GWU's site for undergraduate research articles
- Organize pitch meetings, editing process, and final publication
- Edit for conciseness and clarity from a layperson's perspective

Aug 2021 - Present

Lead Natural Sciences Editor | GW Undergraduate Review, Washington, DC

- Select and edit exemplary scientific research articles for a general audience
- Recruit journal submissions from STEM research students
- Delegate editing process between authors and editors

additional skills

- Web design (WIX, Drupal, Wordpress)
- Microsoft Office Suite

- Adobe Suite (Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere, InDesign)
- Social media management (Sprout Social, Ink.bio)